So far in this lesson we've talked about the reasons we have meetings and we've proposed a very simple
到目前为止，在本课中，我们已经讨论了我们开会的原因，并且我们提出了一个非常简单的
solution to an issue with company culture.
解决公司文化问题。
This is the situation.
这是这种情况。
There are five or six people at this meeting.
这次会议有五六个人。
The person in charge of the meeting is called the moderator.
会议负责人称为主持人。
Now this could be the boss of these people but not necessarily.
现在这可能是这些人的老板，但不一定。
Perhaps not.
也许不是。
They say all right.
他们说好吧。
So I've asked each of you to prepare a proposal for this issue that we're talking about today about
所以我要求你们每个人为我们今天讨论的这个问题准备一份提案
morale among the staff.
员工之间的士气。
Larry I'd like you to start.
拉里，我希望你开始。
Could you give your proposal about the company dinner.
你能就公司晚宴提出你的建议吗？
So then Larry stands up and he gives his proposal about the monthly dinner the idea that I just mentioned.
于是拉里站了起来，他提出了我刚才提到的关于每月晚餐的建议。
Now the other people might have some questions and some feedback once he's given his proposal.
现在，一旦他提出建议，其他人可能会有一些问题和一些反馈。
Sometimes it will be after Larry finishes with the proposal and sometimes it will be in the middle.
有时会在拉里完成提案之后，有时会在中间。
They might want to stop him now.
他们现在可能想阻止他。
That's usually not the best idea.
这通常不是最好的主意。
But there are times when you need to cut in and I'm going to share some basically phrases that you can
但有时你需要插话，我将分享一些基本的短语，你可以
use when you want to then give feedback on an idea when you want to cut in sometimes or when you want
在您想插话时使用，然后在您想插话或想插话时就某个想法提供反馈
to just offer an opinion.
只是提供意见。
Whether you agree or disagree.
不管你同意还是不同意。
So Larry has given his proposal on the monthly dinner and how he thinks it could solve the issue.
所以拉里就每月的晚餐提出了他的建议，以及他认为如何解决这个问题。
Now there might be a simple questions of course you can.
现在可能有一个简单的问题你当然可以。
Once it's over just ask what what costs what costs would be associated with holding the dinner and and
一旦结束，只需询问举办晚宴的费用是多少，以及
who or which department would maybe be responsible which can buy RSP responsible for the budget.
谁或哪个部门可能负责购买负责预算的 RSP。
OK so this is just a follow up question.
好的，所以这只是一个后续问题。
A follow up question.
一个后续问题。
Larry didn't give a lot of detail about the cost involved.
拉里没有详细说明所涉及的成本。
So I have a question about that.
所以我有一个问题。
So this is a good way to often explore something.
所以这是经常探索某事的好方法。
And if you disagree with somebody make them realize that their suggestion is maybe not great.
如果你不同意某人，让他们意识到他们的建议可能不是很好。
I'm not saying Larry suggestion is bad but for example I think it's way too expensive.
我并不是说拉里的建议不好，但例如我认为它太贵了。
And instead of saying I disagree I think it's too expensive.
而不是说我不同意，我认为它太贵了。
Instead I say what costs would be involved.
相反，我会说会涉及哪些成本。
And then Larry has to answer the question and maybe when he answers the question maybe he realizes that
然后拉里必须回答这个问题，也许当他回答这个问题时，他可能意识到
it's too expensive.
太贵。
So one way of disagreeing is making the person who suggested the idea realize that there's something
所以一种不同意的方式是让提出这个想法的人意识到有一些东西
about their idea that's not realistic.
关于他们不现实的想法。
That's one way to do it.
这是一种方法。
Now maybe you just use this question what costs would be associated or involved and also say involved
现在，也许您只是使用这个问题会关联或涉及哪些成本，并且还说涉及
with holding the dinner.
与举行晚宴。
Maybe we just want to know maybe we're not actually trying to criticize maybe we're not trying to say
也许我们只是想知道也许我们实际上并不想批评也许我们不想说
I disagree but that's OK too.
我不同意，但这也没关系。
This is very simple and asking these sorts of questions is very important.
这很简单，提出这类问题非常重要。
So you can just once the person is finished talking ask these simple follow on or follow up questions
因此，您可以在对方说完后询问这些简单的后续问题或后续问题
but what if we want to stop Larry in the middle of his proposal in the middle of his presentation about
但是如果我们想阻止拉里在他的提案中途在他的演讲中
this this idea.
这个这个想法。
Well then we can use a couple of expressions we could use if I may if I may.
好吧，如果可以的话，我们可以使用一些我们可以使用的表达方式。
We can use if if I can cut in for a second or we could say moment and if we really wanted to we could
我们可以使用 if if I can cut in a second or we can say the moment 如果我们真的想的话，我们可以
say hold on a moment.
说等一下。
Hold on a moment and then we say our opinion now that one could be considered a little bit rude to say
稍等片刻，然后我们现在说出我们的意见，这样说可能会被认为有点粗鲁
hold on a moment because it's like saying wait stop talking I need to say something and it's urgent.
稍等片刻，因为它就像说等等别说我有话要说，而且很紧急。
Generally you want to give feedback in a meeting after but if it's really really important to say it
一般来说，你想在会议结束后提供反馈，但如果说出来真的很重要
now then you can use these phrases.
现在你可以使用这些短语了。
So let's look at examples for each of these if I may I would like to say that the cost isn't justified.
因此，如果我想说成本不合理，让我们看一下这些示例。
I don't think I don't think it's worth it.
我不认为我认为这不值得。
OK.
好的。
Now then we can start to have a conversation about that point or maybe Larry can continue with his presentation
现在我们可以开始就这一点进行对话，或者拉里可以继续他的演讲
and then we can talk about that after.
然后我们可以稍后再谈。
But I use if I may if I may.
但如果可以的话，我会使用。
I don't think that the cost is really justifiable.
我不认为成本真的是合理的。
It's pretty expensive to hold a monthly dinner is it really going to be worth it.
每月举行一次晚餐是相当昂贵的，这真的值得吗？
I think the cost might outweigh outweigh the advantages of holding a monthly dinner like that.
我认为成本可能超过每月举行一次这样的晚餐的好处。
So that's a way to get in there to cut in and stop it.
所以这是一种进入并阻止它的方法。
The other one then is if I can cut in if I can cut in I think there might be other ways to boost morale
另一个是如果我能插话，如果我能插话，我认为可能还有其他方法可以提高士气
without breaking the bank.
在不破坏银行的情况下。
Such as.
如。
And then we could say the idea such as some for example team building exercises during working hours.
然后我们可以说一些想法，例如在工作时间进行团队建设练习。
That would be a lot cheaper.
那会便宜很多。
All we have to do is hire a trainer or someone who does team building exercises for example.
我们所要做的就是聘请一名培训师或进行团队建设练习的人。
OK.
好的。
If I can cut in or we could say if I can just cut in again.
如果我可以插话，或者我们可以说我是否可以再次插话。
It's an interruption.
这是一个中断。
Another way to suggest this.
另一种建议方式。
Hold on for a moment.
稍等片刻。
I mentioned before.
我之前提到过。
I don't quite see how a meal is the best way to address address here means deal with deal with address
我不太明白吃饭是如何解决地址的最佳方式在这里意味着处理处理地址
this.
这个。
Each person would be at a small table.
每个人都会坐在一张小桌子旁。
That means for example if the reason for this proposal is to make everybody talk with other people and
这意味着，例如，如果这个提议的原因是让每个人都与其他人交谈，并且
create bonds or connections between them.
在它们之间建立联系或联系。
Well if you're sitting with four or five other people is there really a huge benefit right.
好吧，如果你和其他四五个人坐在一起，真的会有很大的好处。
Maybe if there's a way to get everybody to really do something together maybe that would be a lot better.
也许如果有办法让每个人真正一起做某事，那可能会好得多。
OK.
好的。
So this person again disagrees.
所以这个人又不同意了。
I don't quite see how a meal.
我不太明白一顿饭如何。
OK now this is a very gentle way.
好的，现在这是一种非常温和的方式。
So hold on for a moment is not super polite.
所以稍等片刻也不是超级客气。
This could be considered a bit rude if it's an interruption.
如果这是一个中断，这可能会被认为有点粗鲁。
On for a moment.
开一会儿。
Hold on for a moment.
稍等片刻。
But then this I don't quite see how what you said is correct.
但是，我不太明白您所说的是否正确。
I don't quite see how what you're saying makes sense is a very soft and gentle way to communicate the
我不太明白你说的有什么意义是一种非常柔和和温和的沟通方式
idea that you completely disagree.
你完全不同意的想法。
Again adding quite quite makes it a lot softer if you say I completely disagree then that's a lot more
如果您说我完全不同意，那么再次添加相当相当会使它变得更柔和，那就更多了
direct.
直接的。
OK.
好的。
So anytime you want to softly or gently disagree.
因此，无论何时您想轻声或温和地反对。
Use this.
用这个。
I don't quite see how that would work or I don't quite agree.
我不太明白这将如何工作，或者我不太同意。
One way to tell somebody you disagree is to create a hypothetical possibility that if it's put into
告诉某人你不同意的一种方法是创造一个假设的可能性，如果它被放入
place there would be some negative result.
地方会有一些负面的结果。
So you can say it like that.
所以你可以这样说。
Let's say his Larry's presentation is over it has ended right.
假设他的拉里的演讲结束了，它已经结束了。
He's done with his proposal now and I don't agree with it.
他现在已经完成了他的提议，我不同意。
OK.
好的。
So I could say if we did that if we did that it would completely destroy our events budget one meaning
所以我可以说，如果我们这样做了，如果我们这样做了，那将完全破坏我们的活动预算一个意义
of budget is an amount of money that you have for a specific purpose.
预算是您为特定目的而拥有的金额。
It's there for events things that happen within the company.
它是为了事件 公司内部发生的事情。
So if we did this every month.
所以如果我们每个月都这样做。
Well then we're not going to have any money for anything else.
那么我们不会有任何钱用于其他任何事情。
So if we did that hypothetical if we did that it would.
因此，如果我们这样做，假设我们这样做了。
Can we use wood when we want to create a hypothetical non real situation hypothetical.
当我们想创建一个假设的非真实情况假设时，我们可以使用木头吗？
And it's a really powerful way to disagree because we're stating a fact.
这是一种非常有效的不同意方式，因为我们在陈述一个事实。
What we think is a fact that would happen if this specific plan is put into action.
我们认为，如果将这一具体计划付诸实施，将会发生的事实。
So it's actually very powerful it can be very powerful if you use it well create that hypothetical and
所以它实际上非常强大，如果你用得好，它会非常强大。
make everyone else realize Oh yeah wow we would have no money for anything else.
让其他人意识到哦，是的，哇，我们将没有钱购买其他任何东西。
That sounds terrible.
这听起来很可怕。
And then if we really wanted to add it we could add it to any of these disagreements we could just say
然后如果我们真的想添加它，我们可以将它添加到任何这些分歧中，我们可以说
I don't think it makes sense.
我不认为这是有道理的。
I don't I don't think it makes sense.
我不认为这没有道理。
Whenever somebody gives you an idea about what they think should be done generally we can use.
每当有人给你一个关于他们认为应该做什么的想法时，我们通常可以使用。
I don't think it makes sense or it doesn't make sense.
我认为这没有意义或没有意义。
It's a great way to disagree but then usually you have to explain why it doesn't make sense.
这是不同意的好方法，但通常你必须解释为什么它没有意义。
Now maybe you're thinking wait a second everything you've said so far is to disagree.
现在，也许你在想等一下，到目前为止你所说的一切都是不同意的。
Well that's because it's very easy to agree if you agree then you can just say yeah I agree.
那是因为如果你同意很容易同意，那么你可以说是的，我同意。
Or you could say great idea.
或者你可以说好主意。
Brilliant proposal.
绝妙的提议。
I like it.
我喜欢。
But then you could maybe mention one specific issue.
但是你可能会提到一个具体的问题。
I like it but do we have enough money for this just to ask the question.
我喜欢它，但我们有足够的钱来问这个问题吗？
Let's do it let's do it.
让我们去做吧。
Great idea let's do it.
好主意，让我们去做吧。
I think it's perfect.
我认为这是完美的。
I think it's a great plan.
我认为这是一个很棒的计划。
So it's very easy to agree with a proposal and then ask a follow up question about some of the details.
所以很容易同意一个提案，然后就一些细节提出后续问题。
It's a little bit more complicated to disagree.
不同意有点复杂。
So I hope these phrases that we've learned about how to respond and give feedback based on our proposal
所以我希望我们学到的这些短语是关于如何根据我们的建议做出回应和提供反馈的
are clear because they're all very very common.
很清楚，因为它们都很常见。
And most of them can be used in many many other situations as well outside of just meetings.
而且它们中的大多数可以用于许多其他情况以及会议之外。